<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Daily | EOF]]></title>
  <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/categories/daily/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-03T22:52:46+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jasonleaster.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Leaster]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jasonleaster@163.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Should We Focus on ?]]></title>
    <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2015/06/17/what-should-we-focus-on/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-17T02:46:15+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2015/06/17/what-should-we-focus-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays, people use the social networks like <code>Facebook</code>, <code>Weibo</code>, <code>Qzone</code> and so on. That social networks make you feel that you live with others who have no relationship with you in real life. And more and more people pay a lot of time to refresh the website or the software which is programed for social networks. So did I …</p>

<p>The most important fact is that the message comes from the social networks didn’t help us a lot. If you pay the same time to read a classical book or work hard on your projects, you will get more.</p>

<p>But you choose to refresh your social networks and fall into it. You may know that you are wasting time but you still focus on it. Something like drug … yes, you are drugging but in a different way. Social networks also let you indulge yourself with idle and feel hollow after you have waste a lot of time on that. Day after day, you get nothing but only feel more and more hollow. You know that people live well from the message which the social networks feed you.</p>

<p>Times always change, there will be more and more temptation. But the thing we should know is that we should learn to distinguish what’s important and what just kill us by wating our time.</p>

<p>I delete all message I posted on <code>Weibo</code> and <code>Qzone</code>. In previous days, I followed more than two hundred people in <code>Weibo</code>. To be honest, people I followed most don’t know me and have nothing with my own life. Why I follow them just because I curious about what happened on their daily life. In the beginning, it’s funny. But now I delete them all. Yep, I wake up to reality! It have onthing with my life! I shouldn’t waste time on others who isn’t important for me. WE DO HAVE OUROWN LIFE.</p>

<p>I like a motto from steve jobs.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you want to live your life in a creative way, as an artist, you have to not look back too much. You have to be willing to take whatever you’ve done and whoever you were and throw them away. People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on. But that’s not what it means at all. It means saying not to the hundred other good ideas that there be. You have to pick carefully. I’m actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.</p></blockquote>

<p>What I want to say is that</p>

<blockquote><p>“Focus on yourself :)”.</p></blockquote>

<hr />

<p>Photo by Jason Leaster</p>

<p><img src="/images/img_for_2015_06_17/street.png" alt="images" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
