<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Essay | EOF]]></title>
  <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/categories/essay/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-11T22:28:44+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jasonleaster.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Leaster]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jasonleaster@163.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary for 2016 Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2017/01/11/summary-for-2016-year/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-11T22:07:11+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2017/01/11/summary-for-2016-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking back this year, for leaving school and beginning to my career life, there have many changes, twists and turns in my life. There also have many moved and warm moments in this year. At the last day of this year, they all gone.</p>

<p>Last year, this time, I was busy in my school for finishing my graduation project “E-Face”. Particulary, I want to say thanks to my teacher Hongzhong Tang. Without her encouragement, I can’t do it well. It amost costs my half year time to finish this project.</p>

<p>Daily, I read paper about face detection. I pay a lot of time to code, debug and verify my new idea about the implementation.</p>

<p>It’s about March and April. One day, my father call me and tell me that he felt not good. After the short call, I knew he need a surgery. Before the day when he has been performed the operation, I go back home to accompany him. He spent about six hours to finish his operation. During that time, I waited out sideof the door of the OR(operating room) all the time. After that, I stay at home for a month to accompany him and help him to recover.</p>

<p>June, thesis defense, take the diploma,  pack up and quit. I don’t feel happy for graduation nor sad for leaving. I just leave the place where I think it’s like a naive garden. From my perspective, school like a cage. They have a lot of things in common. Teenagers can’t adapt to industrial society, so adult set many rules for them and keep them in a place to avoid to be disturbed by the little guys.</p>

<p>Carrying heavy suitcases, it took me about 12-hours to come to the destination – ShenZhen, which everybody talk about.</p>

<p>Maybe, it’s for my shallow. I feel nothing different with my hometown but the high prices of daily necessities and the congested road.</p>

<p>It’s already half year ago but I can remeber that clearyly. I was impressed to remember that we lived in a narrow hotel room
 and count how many moneys we have to spent everyday. We are anxious to rent a room but not to live in the hotel for more days. It’s too expensive for two graduate. Looking at the platfond, we sign with feeling how hard the life is.</p>

<p>I think I will remember the first night forever when we came to ShenZhen. We were hungry and go outside to the roadside with my girl friend to eat fried rice with eggs.</p>

<p>For one more month, I finished the induction process and she also found a job. We got start the “loop” of work, get off work, eat and sleep. There are lots of unstable factors in my life but it’s not that bad, isn’t it?</p>

<p>Thanks for my family and annabella. Without them, I can’t tell how can I get through this time.</p>

<p>This week, we get two tickets to get back home for Chinese New Year, which means that 2016 is ending. Finally, I wish my family and annabella’s family is health. Annabella will get a good job and stay with me as always.</p>

<p>2016 is ending, 2017 is coming. Wish you are becoming someone who you want to be. EOF.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Be wrong or right <br />
Sometimes you’ve got to sacrifice the things you like <br />
But I was born to try   <br />
No point in talking what you should have been <br />
And regretting the things that went on<br />
Life’s full of mistakes, destinies and fate<br />
Remove the clouds look at the bigger picture<br />
And all that you see is me<br />
And all I truly believe <br />
     – « Born To Try » Delta Goodrem</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<p>Photo by Annabella.</p>

<p><img src="http://jasonleaster.github.io/images/img_for_2017_01/MeAtShenZhenNorthStation.jpg" width="800" align="middle" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Should We Focus on ?]]></title>
    <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2015/06/17/what-should-we-focus-on/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-17T02:46:15+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2015/06/17/what-should-we-focus-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays, people use the social networks like <code>Facebook</code>, <code>Weibo</code>, <code>Qzone</code> and so on. That social networks make you feel that you live with others who have no relationship with you in real life. And more and more people pay a lot of time to refresh the website or the software which is programed for social networks. So did I …</p>

<p>The most important fact is that the message comes from the social networks didn’t help us a lot. If you pay the same time to read a classical book or work hard on your projects, you will get more.</p>

<p>But you choose to refresh your social networks and fall into it. You may know that you are wasting time but you still focus on it. Something like drug … yes, you are drugging but in a different way. Social networks also let you indulge yourself with idle and feel hollow after you have waste a lot of time on that. Day after day, you get nothing but only feel more and more hollow. You know that people live well from the message which the social networks feed you.</p>

<p>Times always change, there will be more and more temptation. But the thing we should know is that we should learn to distinguish what’s important and what just kill us by wating our time.</p>

<p>I delete all message I posted on <code>Weibo</code> and <code>Qzone</code>. In previous days, I followed more than two hundred people in <code>Weibo</code>. To be honest, people I followed most don’t know me and have nothing with my own life. Why I follow them just because I curious about what happened on their daily life. In the beginning, it’s funny. But now I delete them all. Yep, I wake up to reality! It have onthing with my life! I shouldn’t waste time on others who isn’t important for me. WE DO HAVE OUROWN LIFE.</p>

<p>I like a motto from steve jobs.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you want to live your life in a creative way, as an artist, you have to not look back too much. You have to be willing to take whatever you’ve done and whoever you were and throw them away. People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on. But that’s not what it means at all. It means saying not to the hundred other good ideas that there be. You have to pick carefully. I’m actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>What I want to say is that</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Focus on yourself :)”.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />
<p>Photo by Jason Leaster</p>

<p><img src="/images/img_for_2015_06_17/street.png" alt="images" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Means Freedom ?]]></title>
    <link href="http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/what-means-freedom/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T00:46:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jasonleaster.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/what-means-freedom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What does it mean to be free? Free is being able to choose. To choose your own space to be in. To form your surrounding in a way that will make you to take out the best of you. Free is to say no. Get your freedom …</p>

<p><img src="/images/img_for_What_means_freedom/freedom.png" alt="images" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
